So, what do you wear for performing for belly dancing?
Hi, I'm Johanna Kryntyzky from Hip Expressions Belly Dance Studio in St. Petersburg, Florida.
Let's talk about the latest fashions in belly dancing costuming.
Now you may be familiar with the traditional bra a and belt, which usually goes on over a big, full skirt.
This style of costuming was very popular in the 1970's when belly dancing first came to America and became very, very popular in some of the Greek and Turkish night clubs.
Lately, you're going to find some fashions coming out of Egypt, such as this.
I got this from Joe Hurrah, who's a fashion designer in Miami.
And what we have now is we're seeing more of these one skirt, where there's no separate belt attached, the bead work is actually on the skirt.
So you'll find that in the bras, again, very similar, a little more clean cut.
Not so much fringe hanging down.
It's very traditional to have lots of fringe in the Turkish style costumes.
So we're looking at seeing a stream lined look, and we're also seeing a bit more of these cut outs that you'll find.
So they'll be cut outs down the side of the leg.
Now, always in belly dance costuming, you want to consider your audience, and you want it to be appropriate for your audience.
So you want something that's fashionable and tasteful, and looks great on you.
I'm Johanna Krynytzky with Hip Expressions Belly Dance Studio, helping you with the latest fashions in belly dance.